# J. Michael Brown

# Full Stack Software Engineer

Beaverton, OR 97007 (503) 702-8810 imichaelbrown.codes@gmail.com | https://imichaelbrown.codes https://github.com/jmichaelbrown8 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/jmichaelbrown/

## **SUMMARY**

Agile software delivery expert, with 4 years of front end web development experience and 6 years of software team process leadership. Enthusiastic about teaching, mentoring, coaching, and continuing to learn along with a close-knit team. Passionate about simplifying the complex and using data to inform decisions.

### **SKILLS**

JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL, MongoDB NodeJS, Express, React, GraphQL, MUI, jQuery, Bootstrap AWS: Cloudfront, Route53, S3, Lambda, EC2, Cloudformation Meeting Facilitation, Story Mapping, Wireframing, Leading Continuous Improvement

# **PROJECTS**

Will It Fit? | https://will-it-fit-app.herokuapp.com | https://github.com/imichaelbrown8/will-it-fit

- Social network for connecting with users of similar size to share clothes that fit
- Built with MongoDB/Mongoose, GraphQL/Apollo, NodeJS, and React/MUI

Elevator Pitch | https://elevatorpitch.space | https://github.com/imichaelbrown8/elevator-pitch

- Collaboration web app to pitch ideas and form project groups
- Built with MySQL/Sequelize, NodeJS/Express, Handlebars/jQuery, and Bootstrap

Mobber | https://jmichaelbrown8.github.io/mobber | https://github.com/jmichaelbrown8/mobber

- A timer app to help manage rotations in collaborative programming sessions
- Built with React/Redux, and MUI

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Nike, Inc. Beaverton, OR

Sr. Scrum Master

JANUARY 2020 - PRESENT

- Coach and facilitate collaboration to deliver software across 7 web front end, native app, and back end software teams for the cart and checkout experiences for nike.com and the Nike iOS and Android apps
- Advocate for the developer community by speaking at an engineering forum, coaching community meetup facilitators to create compelling content and drive engagement, and contributing code to the developer community infrastructure built with React and GraphQL

- Wrote Python scripts to collect and summarize team data from the JIRA API, which was adopted by Digital Dash, an enterprise-wide dashboard for team metrics
- Created dashboards with React to visualize agility metrics and project burndowns
- Created games in React to teach the Scrum framework and the Edge team's high-level diagrams
- Led community of practice meetups to develop agile and software engineering skills of my colleagues
- Facilitated software architecture and blueprint delivery for Architecture and Core Components teams
- Created a Node EC2 app to log Hystrix events to Splunk, deployed with an in-house automated pipeline

Eleven Wireless Portland, OR

# Software Engineer / Scrum Master

**APRIL 2014 - APRIL 2016** 

- Maintained RESTful web services and updated SQL stored procedures for a network admin back end
- Set up Route53 entries and Cloudfront distributions for hosting customer websites
- Designed and implemented a custom content delivery network to push network access portals directly to cruise ships, resulting in a 20x improvement in page load times

Web Developer APRIL 2013 - APRIL 2014

- Added localization and mobile-responsive design to an in-house Content Management System
- Designed and developed intuitive interfaces to manage complex network tools using Angular JS

Jr. Web Developer JULY 2012 - APRIL 2013

- Created brand templates with HTML, CSS, JS, and jQuery for custom hotel internet access websites
- Wrote a Python build and deploy script to automate portal deployment that integrated with AWS S3

Legend3D San Diego, CA

Asset Technician / Sr. Asset Technician

NOVEMBER 2010 - JUNE 2012

- Python scripting to automate movie still ingestion, resulting in fewer errors and faster processing
- Leading process improvement and documentation for the assets department

Yahoo! Music Santa Monica, CA

Library Resource / Music Director

MAY 2009 - NOVEMBER 2010

- A/V Recording, editing, and transcoding of music videos, interviews, and in-office performances
- HTML blog and email publishing for Yahoo! Music homepage and partner communications

## **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS**

University of Washington, Seattle, WA (Remote) - Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp

**ICAgile, Beaverton, OR** - ICAgile Certified Professional: Agile Team Facilitation, Agile Coaching, Coaching Agile Transition, Agility in the Enterprise

edX/MitX, Online - Fundamentals of Computer Science Certificate

Scrum Alliance, Portland, OR - Certified ScrumMaster and Certified Scrum Product Owner

**University of California, San Diego** - B.A. Interdisciplinary Computing and the Arts - Music